

□+1 (734) 496-1803 | ☑jwnchung@umich.edu | ₳ jaewonchung.me | ☑jaywonchung | jae-won-chung-cs

# Summary .

I am a second year PhD student in CSE at the University of Michigan, working with Professor Mosharaf Chowdhury. My research interest is in the intersection of software systems and deep learning, with a recent focus on sustainability aspects such as energy consumption and carbon footprint. I lead the ML Energy initiative.

### **Education**

**University of Michigan** 

Ann Arbor, MI, USA

Ph.D. STUDENT IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Sep 2021 - present

**Seoul National University** 

Seoul, South Korea

B.S. IN ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Mar 2015 - Aug 2021

- GPA: 4.04/4.3 (overall) 4.15/4.3 (major), Summa Cum Laude
- · Period includes two years of military service.

### **Publications**

- Zeus: Understanding and Optimizing GPU Energy Consumption of DNN Training, Jie You\*, <u>Jae-Won Chung</u>\* (\*: co-primary authors), Mosharaf Chowdhury, Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2023 (Acceptance rate = 18.38%)
- ShadowTutor: Distributed Partial Distillation for Mobile Video DNN Inference, Jae-Won Chung, Jae-Yun Kim, Soo-Mook Moon, International Conference on Parallel Processing (ICPP), 2020 (Acceptance rate = 28.99%)

# **Experience**

SymbioticLab UMich, United States

GRADUATE STUDENT RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Sep 2022 - Present

- · Advised by Professor Mosharaf Chowdhury.
- Zeus: Discovered the trade-off between DNN training time and energy. Designed a Multi-Armed Bandit solution for time-energy optimization.

Software Platform Lab SNU, South Korea

RESEARCH INTERN Apr 2020 - Jun 2022

• Developed Crane, a GPU cluster manager for AutoML workloads. Built a Kubernetes backend that scaled to 288 GPUs.

#### **Virtual Machine and Optimization Lab**

SNU, South Korea

SENIOR PROJECT

Dec 2019 - Jun 2020

• ShadowTutor: Online model specialization for edge video inference. Use of knowledge distillation reduced network data transfer by 95%.

Computer Vision Lab SNU, South Korea

Undergraduate Intern

Jun 2019 - Dec 2019

• Designed improved meta-initialization methods for Model-Agnostic Meta-Learning (MAML) with neural memory modules and convex programs.

### **Lab of Imaging Science and Technology**

SNU, South Korea

Undergraduate Intern

Jun 2019 - Aug 2019

• Designed and implemented a full deep learning pipeline for Quantitative Susceptibility Mapping, a vision task for 3D MRI field data.

DECEMBER 14, 2022 JAE-WON CHUNG · RÉSUMÉ

## **Honors & Awards**

Nov 2022 **Carbon Hack '22 Second Best Solution**, Carbon-Aware DNN Training with Zeus, \$25,000

Jul 2021 Kwanjeong Overseas Scholarship, \$100,000 over four years

Mar 2019 **Kwanjeong Undergraduate Scholarship**, \$20,000 over two years

Green Software Foundation Kwanjeong Educational Foundation Kwanjeong Educational Foundation

# **Teaching**

• Spring 2021 Operating Systems, Main TA, Managed course projects and led group design reviews.

• Fall 2020 Computer Organization (Undergraduate architecture), Peer tutor, Provided 30 hours of online lecture, Best Tutor Award!

### Skills.

**Language** Python, Rust, CUDA, C++, Verilog, C, Bash **Framework** PyTorch, Pandas, Matplotlib, FastAPI

**Methodology** Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Multi-Armed Bandit

Tool Docker, Kubernetes, KubeFlow, LaTeX

English TOEFL 120 (Perfect score), GRE 167/170/4.5